

Aarhus, Denmark

(+45) 2991 3001 ▼ Tue.Boesen@protonmail.com tueboesen Tue Boesen

Summary_

I am a data scientist specialized in machine learning. I have worked both as: researcher, project lead, and technical advisor/consultant on various projects. I have a solid foundation in: mathematics, data science, and general optimization techniques. Within machine learning, I have specialised in physics-informed and graph neural networks, but I have experience with most areas of deep learning.

Selected experience _____

Proteic Bioscience Inc. Vancouver Canada

MACHINE LEARNING CONSULTANT

Jan 2022 - June 2022

- · Lead and developed an equivariant neural networks for energy and force predictions for biomolecular systems.
- Developed a parallel framework for protein design using PyRosetta.
- · Optimized neural network hyper parameters using Optuna.

University of Bristish Columbia (UBC)

Vancouver, Canada

May 2019 - Aug 2021

- POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH FELLOW IN MACHINE LEARNING
- Developed novel physics-informed neural network frameworks.
- · Published reversible mimetic graph neural networks.
- · Developed self-supervised conditional probability neural networks inspired by natural language processing models.
- Published a semi-supervised active learning algorithm.
- Deployed large scale training on Amazon Web Services.

Computational Geoscience Inc.

Vancouver, Canada

Al Research Scientist

May 2019 - Aug 2020

- Developed clustering techniques for oil exploration.
- Published novel graph-based semi-supervised learning methods applied to seismic data.

HydroGeophysics Group at Aarhus University

Aarhus, Denmark

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug 2017 - Nov 2017

 Open-sourced a sparse iterative parallel linear solver based on my research during my Ph.D. • Open-sourced an OpenMP parallelization framework developed during my Ph.D.

Danske Bank Copenhagen, Denmark

ANALYST, GRADUATE POSITION

Sep 2013 - Apr 2014

· Worked in customer insight creating forecast models.

HydroGeophysics Group at Aarhus University

Aarhus, Denmark

SCIENTIFIC PROGRAMMING CONSULTANT

Mar 2013 - Sep 2013

· Created SPIA in Pascal, an application for ground-based electromagnetic measurements.

Education

Aarhus University Denmark

Ph.D. IN GEOPHYSICS 2015 - 2018

Thesis: Numerical methods for electromagnetic geophysics beyond 1D

Aarhus University Denmark

M.S. IN THEORETICAL PHYSICS

 Thesis: Foundation for a parallel time-dependent density functional theory simulator in a spherical harmonic basis using the exact exchange energy functional

Aarhus University Denmark

2006 - 2010 B.S. IN PHYSICS

• Thesis: Feynmans Pathintegral i 1 dimension med fokus på sinusbaner (Feynman's path integral in 1 dimension with focus on sinusoidal trajectories)

Platforms Windows, Linux Ubuntu, AWS

Programming Python, Pytorch, LaTeX, Git, Matlab, Fortran, Julia, Delphi/Pascal, OpenMp, MPI

Languages Danish, English

Teaching and supervision

Teaching

NSTRUCTOR

Aarhus University, Denmark
2009-2017

Calculus.

• Electric and Electromagnetic methods.

- Data processing and interpretation for groundwater mapping.
- · Geophysical methods.
- · Hydrogeophysical field course (twice).

Supervision UBC, Canado

Co-Supervisor

• Jingrong Lin - Ph.D. student in geophysics and machine learning.

About me

My main hobbies outside work are rock climbing and beach volley. Apart from those I like to tinker with various projects, my current project is to **develop a framework** that can play various boardgames, while previous ones include: building a quadcopter, and designing and building a hangboard with a CNC machine and laser cutter.

Publications

IN PREPARATION

Neural DAEs: Constrained neural networks Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Uri M Ascher arXiv preprint arXiv:2211.14302 (2022). 2022

ACCEPTED

A-optimal active learning
Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber
arXiv preprint arXiv:2110.09585 (2022). 2022

JOURNAL ARTICLES

Mimetic neural networks: a unified framework for protein design and folding Moshe Eliasof, Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, Chen Keasar, Eran Treister Frontiers in Bioinformatics 2 (2022). 2022

Data-driven semi-supervised clustering for oil prediction

Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, G Michael Hoversten

Computers & Geosciences 148 (2021) p. 104684. Pergamon, 2021

An efficient 2D inversion scheme for airborne frequency-domain data

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders Vest Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Casper Kirkegaard, Andreas Aspmo Pfaffhuber, Malte Vöge Geophysics 83.4 (2018) E189–E201. Society of Exploration Geophysicists and American Association of Petroleum ..., 2018

A parallel computing thin-sheet inversion algorithm for airborne time-domain data utilising a variable overburden Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Anders Vest Christiansen, Gianluca Fiandaca, Cyril Schamper

Geophysical Prospecting 66.7 (2018) pp. 1402–1414. European Association of Geoscientists & Engineers, 2018

A review of airborne electromagnetic methods with focus on geotechnical and hydrological applications from 2007 to 2017 Esben Auken, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen

Advances in geophysics 58 (2017) pp. 47–93. Elsevier, 2017

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Semi-supervised clustering for oil prospectivity
Tue Boesen, Eldad Haber, G Michael Hoversten

ICLR AI for Earth Sciences workshop, 2020

Efficient 2D hybrid inversion of airborne frequency domain data E Auken, T Boesen, AVC Christiansen, GF Fiandaca, AA Pfaffhuber, MV Vöge

Second European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2017

2D FEM inversion with a moving footprint and a hybrid 1D and 2D forward and derivative implementation

Tue Boesen, Esben Auken, Malte Vöge, Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Rønne Andersen, Andreas Aspmo Pfaffhuber, Anders Vest Christiansen

AGU Fall Meeting Abstracts, 2016

Rapid inversion of large airborne AEM data datasets utilizing massively parallel co-processors C Kirkegaard, K Andersen, AV Christiansen, E Auken, T Boesen

First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015

Utilizing massively parallel co-processors in the AarhusInv 1D forward and inverse AEM modelling code Casper Kirkegaard, Kristoffer Andersen, Tue Boesen, Anders V Christiansen, Esben Auken, Gianluca Fiandaca ASEG Extended Abstracts, 2015

2.5D inversion of sea ice thickness from helicopter EM data
M Vöge, A Pfaffhuber, E Auken, C Kirkegaard, T Boesen, S Hendricks, P Hunkeler

First European Airborne Electromagnetics Conference, 2015